#### CONTACT

Mobile: +2348063632801 E-mail: Simonokah@gmail.com Location: Lagos, Nigeria

#### **EXPERIENCE**

STUTERN LIMITED
NOV 2019 TILL DATE
FRONT-END SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

**BACK-END SOFTWARE DEVELOPER** 

**FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEERING** 

# **MAKASASUN NIG. LTD**

NETWORK OPERATING CENTER(NOC) ENGINEER 2018-2019

PERFORMANCE/DATA ANALYST 2018-2019

#### **EDUCATION**

Delta State University
BSC MATHEMATICS
2012 - 2015

Neco, Christ The King College Senior Secondary School Certificate Examination 2008

Andela, Google, Udacity
Front End Web Developer Google
Africa scholarship front end course
2018

# OKAH ORUAROGHENE

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **SUMMARY**

"As an ambitious and hard-working individual, I am often recognized for my commitment and ability by companies i have worked with. I handle multiple tasks on a daily basis competently, working well under the pressure. Valuable team member who has experience diagnosing problems and developing solutions. Frequent acknowledgment of my contribution from senior management illustrates my potential value to your company. I would welcome the opportunity to discuss my suitability in more detail."

#### FRONT-END DEVELOPER

- Implementing web design and development principles to build stable software.
- Bringing mock-ups to life using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Collaborating closely with the team to support projects during all phases of delivery.
- Building websites and apps that are responsive and usable.
- Monitoring website performance and rectifying frontend-related issues.
- Communicating technical issues in an understandable manner to the team and clients.
- Identifying innovative ideas and proof of concepts according to project requirements.
- Providing guidance and troubleshooting support to clients.
- Maintaining an organized workflow using a project management tool (like GitHub).
- Testing to identify bugs and technical issues before and after deploying.
- Documenting bug reports, tickets, and any code changes.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **SERVICE YEAR**

Grace Foundation College Ibadan, National Youth Services Corps (NYSC) Mathematics and physics teacher 2016 - 2017

# SOFTWARE SKILLS

- HTML/CSS
- Javascript
- React.is
- Node.is
- Postgressql
- SQL
- Bootstrap

#### OTHER SKILLS

- Microsoft Office
- Strong communication skills
- Fast learner

#### **BACK-END DEVELOPER**

- Working with other developers in delivering internal and external back-end applications.
- Supporting the front-end development team in every way. Making suggestions on how to improve current back-end applications.
- Writing clean and maintainable code.
- Working with remote teams on complex issues.
- Involved in every aspect of the application development process, from early design to testing and launch of the product.
- Co-ordinating with other developers on the delivery of application code.
- Improving existing scripts.Reporting directly to the head of the web development team.Coming up with robust
- solutions that meet client requirements.Interacting with clients and stakeholders on a daily basis.
- Developing new functionality on demand.Extending
- business logic within existing back-end services.

#### **FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

- Developing front end website architecture.
- Designing user interactions on web pages.
- Developing back end website applications.
- Creating servers and databases for functionality.
- Ensuring cross-platform optimization for mobile phones.
- Ensuring responsiveness of applications.

# NETWORK OPERATING CENTER (NOC) ENGINEER MAKASASUN NIG. LTD:

- Network Operations Center (NOC) Engineer / Data Analyst.
- Monitoring large computer networks and servers.
- Solving problems from a central location (Affectli Software Database).
- Analyze problems, perform troubleshooting and incident response on the software database.
- Communicate with site technicians and track problems through till resolution.

# PERFORMANCE / DATA ANALYST MAKASASUN NIG. LTD:

- Interpreting data, analyzing results using statistical techniques.
- Developing and implementing data analyses.
- Data collection systems and other strategies that optimize statistical efficiency and quality.
- Acquiring data from primary or secondary data sources and maintaining databases.